In this video, we're going to set up a full data science environment for Mac users.
이 비디오에선 Mac 사용자를 위한 데이터 과학 환경을 설정할 거예요
In the next video, we'll do PC users.
다음 영상에서는 PC 사용자를 다룰 거예요
So if you're a PC person, please skip to the next.
PC를 지지하신다면 다음 질문으로 넘어가세요
You can you can listen in here if you wish, but otherwise I will see you next time.
듣고 싶으면 여기서 들어요 아니면 다음에 봐요
Okay, so my Mac people now I'm a mac person myself.
좋아요, 맥 피플이∙∙∙ 저도 맥 피플이에요
I've always owned Macs, so you are my home crowd.
전 항상 맥스를 운영해서 여러분이 제 단골이에요
You are definitely my favorites.
제가 제일 좋아하는 분들이에요
It's not like I'm going to say the same thing to the other guys.
다른 남자들한테도 똑같이 말할 건 아니잖아요
Or maybe I am.
그럴지도 모르죠
Anyways, this is looking right now in a Chrome browser at the repo LM engineering in GitHub, and this
깃허브의 LM 엔지니어링 압류 브라우저에 나와 있어요 이 링크가 곳곳에 도배돼
link should hopefully be plastered all over the place, including in the lecture notes for this lecture.
있을 겁니다 이 강의의 강의 노트에도요
Uh, but please come here and look at the GitHub repo, uh, to see the code that we have.
여기 와서 깃허브 압류 좀 보세요 우리가 가진 코드를 보시라고요
Uh, what you'll also see if you scroll down is the contents of the Readme file, which is where I have
스크롤을 내리면 리드메 파일의 내용도 보입니다 환경을 설정하기 위해
laid out what needs to be done to set up your environment.
무엇이 필요한지 표시한 곳이죠
And I hope that I've done a decent job here of laying things out step by step and being clear on what
제가 잘했길 바랍니다 모든 걸 단계별로 잘 배치했고 뭔가 잘못되면 어떤 조치를
action to take, if anything is to go wrong.
취할지 명확히 했으니까요
so hopefully it's good, but if you have any corrections to make to it.
잘 나왔으면 좋겠지만 수정할 부분이 있으면 하세요
As some people already have, for which I'm very grateful, please do let me know and I'll do that.
이미 그런 분들이 계시니 정말 감사하게 생각해요 저한테 알려 주시면 알려 드릴게요
Okay.
네
But for now, what you're going to do is press this green button here code.
하지만 지금은 이 코드 녹색 버튼을 누르세요
And then you can pick either of these two.
이 둘 중 하나를 고르세요
But you're going to pick this copy button here, which is going to copy the URL that identifies this
여기 복사 버튼을 선택하면 이 압류를 식별하는 URL을 클립보드로
repo into the clipboard.
복사하죠
And that is done.
다 됐어요
All right.
좋아요
We're now going to bring up a terminal window where we're going to go next.
이제 터미널 창을 불러오겠습니다 다음에 갈 곳이죠
Now this some of this you can do using the max finder windows if you prefer that.
이것 중 일부는 최대 파인더 창을 이용해 할 수 있어요 그걸 선호한다면요
But I'm more comfortable in terminals and I imagine many of you are too.
하지만 전 터미널이 더 편합니다 여러분도 마찬가지겠죠
So I'm now in my home directory.
이제 홈 디렉터리에 들어왔어요
Many of you will have a projects directory set up, which is where you manage your your projects.
많은 분들이 프로젝트 디렉터리 셋업을 갖고 계실 겁니다 여러분의 프로젝트를 관리하는 곳이죠
At the moment I don't have one set up.
지금은 설치가 안 됐어요
If I do CD projects, there's nothing there.
CD 프로젝트를 하면 아무것도 없어요
So I'm going to make a directory projects and go into it.
디렉터리 프로젝트를 만들고 들어가 볼게요.
Here we go.
시작할게요
And then the next thing I'm going to do when I'm inside the projects folder is I'm going to type git
프로젝트 폴더에서 다음으로 할 일은 git 클론을 입력하는
clone, I want to clone a repo and paste in the name of the repo right there, and when I press enter,
것입니다 압류 깃을 복제하고 압류 깃 이름을 붙여넣습니다 엔터를 누르면 알아서
it does its thing.
작동하죠
And I now have locally an LM engineering folder.
이제 LM 엔지니어링 폴더가 로컬에 있어요
I'm going to go into it and there is all of our code.
들어가 보면 모든 코드가 있어요
It's worth pointing out that where we are right now in the LM engineering folder is what people sometimes
지금 우리가 있는 LM 엔지니어링 폴더는 프로젝트 루트 디렉터리에
call being in the project root directory.
있다고 사람들이 종종 부르는 곳이죠
That's, that's the name for for where we are right now for this project.
그게 이 프로젝트의 현재 위치의 이름이에요
The project root directory LM engineering.
프로젝트 루트 디렉터리 LM 엔지니어링이죠
All right.
좋아요
So the next thing to do is for us to look at installing Anaconda.
다음으로 할 일은 아나콘다 설치예요
If you haven't installed it before.
처음 설치하는 거라면요
And the Readme has a direct link to the installation page at anaconda.com, which will allow you to
리드미에는 아나콘다의 설치 페이지로 직접 링크가 있어요 Mac OS를 설정할 수
set it up for Mac OS.
있게 해주죠
There's a simple set of screens that will go through and configure it.
구성하는 간단한 화면 모음이 있어요
I'm not going to do it because I've already done it for me.
안 할 거예요 이미 해 봤으니까요
But but it is very clearly step by step as you will see it here.
하지만 보시다시피 단계별로 아주 명확해요
And before you know it, you'll have Anaconda on your box when you have anaconda on your box.
그럼 상자에 아나콘다가 붙어 있을 거예요 상자에 아나콘다가 붙어 있을 때요
Back to the terminal window.
터미널 창으로 돌아가죠
Here we are.
여기예요
We simply call a command that tells Anaconda to do everything to build a whole data science environment
아나콘다에게 데이터 과학 환경을 구축하도록 모든 걸 지시하는 명령을
for us, and that command is conda env for environment create minus f, which means we're going to specify
호출합니다 환경을 위한 콘다 부럽기 때문이죠 생성하기 f는 환경에 대한 완전한 설명이 있는
a file which has the full description of the environment.
파일을 지정한다는 뜻이에요
And that name of that file is environment.yml which you can see right here.
저 파일의 이름은 환경이에요 여기서 볼 수 있는 yml이죠
That is the file that defines this environment.
이 환경을 정의하는 파일이죠
And when you've done that you press enter.
다 됐으면 엔터키를 누르세요
Now what's going to happen now is that Anaconda is going to connect to its server, find out everything
이제 아나콘다가 서버에 연결할 겁니다 우리가 해야 할 일을 모두 알아내죠
And it does what it's called solving environment, which means it figures out what versions of each
해결 환경이라는 걸 합니다 필요한 패키지 각각의 버전이 올바른
of the different packages we need are going to be the right versions, that we need to have a fully
버전인지 알아내는 거죠 완전히 호환 가능하고 완전히 지정된 환경이어야
compatible, full specked environment.
하는 거요
And what you saw it just doing there with all of that stuff going on.
이 모든 게 일어나는 걸 보셨을 거예요
Uh, was it, uh, feverishly creating the various, downloading the various packages and building them?
바쁘게 다양한 걸 만들고 다양한 패키지를 다운로드해서 구축했나요?
Now, that might take a fair bit longer for you, because it's fast for me, because I've already done
비트는 시간이 좀 더 걸릴 수도 있어요 전 이미 해봤거든요
it and it's cached locally the first time it needs to download it.
처음 다운로드 할 때 로컬에 캐시돼 있어요
For me, I have a pretty good internet connection, and it took about five minutes.
저는 인터넷 연결이 잘돼서 5분 정도 걸렸어요
The first time I did this, someone reported that it was taking more than 20 minutes for them.
처음 이걸 했을 때 20분 이상 걸린다는 보고를 받았어요
Uh, which is of course, uh, yeah, a lot of time to wait.
물론 기다릴 시간이 많다는 뜻이죠
So if it's taking that long, then that might be if you have a slower internet connection that might
그렇게 오래 걸린다면 예상되는 느린 인터넷 연결이 있을
be expected.
때죠
But if it takes much longer than 20 minutes and you have a good internet connection, then something's
하지만 20분 이상 걸리는데 인터넷 연결이 잘 된다면 아나콘다에게
not working with Anaconda.
문제가 생긴 거죠
And I would cancel it with command C, and instead we'll use the other approach, the virtual environment
명령 C로 취소하고 다른 접근법을 사용합니다 가상 환경
approach instead.
접근법이죠
So right now, Anaconda is busy doing what it calls executing the transaction, which is essentially
지금 아나콘다는 트랜잭션을 실행하는 데 한창입니다 기본적으로 필요한 버전의
after it's figured out what versions of what we need, It's building that that whole environment.
어떤 것이 필요한지 알아낸 다음 전체 환경을 구축하죠
And then at the end, for those that know about this, there are also some packages that I pip install
그리고 이걸 아시는 분들을 위해 제가 설치한 패키지도 있습니다
because they're not they don't yet have conda versions.
왜냐하면 아직 콘다 버전이 없거든요
So there are some packages that get pip installed at the end of it.
끝에 get이 설치되는 패키지가 있어요
But when you see installing pip install you are near the very end and it's done.
하지만 피프를 설치할 때는 거의 다 끝나가요
So I didn't lie.
거짓말은 안 했어요
It doesn't need to take a long amount of time.
오래 걸릴 필요가 없어요
It's pretty fast and all of that is done.
정말 빠르네요 다 끝났어요
We need to activate our new environment, which means we need to say we want that to be the live environment
새 환경을 활성화해야 합니다 현재 사용 중인 라이브 환경이 되어야
that's currently being used.
한다는 뜻이죠
If you look at my my cursor right now, you'll see the word base is to the left here.
지금 제 커서를 보시면 왼쪽에 있는 단어가 보이시죠
And that means that we're not currently running in an in an anaconda environment right at the moment.
그 말은 현재 아나콘다 환경에서 실행되고 있지 않다는 거죠
In order to use our LM environment, we the name of the environment is LMS and we're going to type conda
LM 환경을 사용하기 위해 환경 이름은 LMS입니다 콘다가 LMS를
activate LMS.
활성화한다고 입력하죠
And that is all it takes to tell Anaconda we want to be running in this environment with the same version
아나콘다에게 이 환경에서 파이썬 버전을 실행하고 싶다고 말하는 데 필요한 게 그것뿐인가요?
of Python, the same version of all of these packages?
패키지들도 다 같은 버전이고요?
That means that we are completely consistent.
일관성이 있다는 뜻이죠
That happened immediately, and you'll see that LMS is now written on the left.
즉시 그렇게 됐죠 LMS가 왼쪽에 쓰인 게 보이시죠
And if you're seeing that, that is your clue that it's worked and that you are now running the right
그걸 보신다면 그게 성공했다는 단서고 올바른 버전의 아나콘다를 실행하고
version of Anaconda.
있다는 거죠
And as a final step here, I type in this command JupyterLab.
마지막 단계로 command JupyterLab을 입력할게요
And JupyterLab is the command that says, I want to launch this data science environment called JupyterLab,
JupyterLab은 명령이에요 JupyterLab이라는 데이터 과학 환경을 실행하고
which allows me to work very interactively with code.
싶어요 코드와 상호 작용하며 작업할 수 있도록 해주죠
And when I run that, it thinks for hopefully just a moment while it considers the task at hand.
실행하면 잠시 생각하죠 당면한 작업을 고려하는 동안에요
And then it will launch JupyterLab in a new screen.
그럼 새로운 화면에서 주피터랩을 시작할 거예요
And what you will probably see is something a bit like this.
아마 이런 비트를 보게 될 거예요
All right.
좋아요
With that, I'm now going to pause for you guys.
이것과 함께 잠시 멈출게요
I'm going to record a video for the PC users, and I'll meet you back in two videos time.
PC 사용자들을 위해 영상을 찍고 두 영상 후에 다시 만나요
See you there.
거기서 봐요